勇气更新中心
教学勇气澄心委员会
澄心委员会是一个
The clearness committee is a process
在贵格会社区中有400年历史的过程，
that is 400 years old among the Quaker community
我们为教学勇气运动对其进行了改编。
that we have adapted for the courage to teach.
简单地说，它包括
It consists to put it simply of
一个人带着他或她
a person with an issue or a problem
正在挣扎的问题或难题，
that he or she is wrestling with,
和其他五六个人一起，
sitting for two to three hours,
坐上两三个小时,
with five or six other people
在会议的前10分钟左右，
that focused person so-called presents his or her
所谓的焦点人物提出他或她的问题。
problem in the first 10 minutes or so of the meeting.
然后在接下来的两个小时，
And then for the next two hours
或者其它时段里，
or whatever time remains a long period of time,
委员会成员被禁止
members of the committee are
以任何方式与焦点人物说话，
forbidden to speak to the focused person
除了问一个诚实而开放的问题。
in any way except to ask an honest open question.
我们会在什么构成了
And we do a lot of work on
一个诚实而开放的问题上做了许多阐释。
what constitutes an honest open question.
如果我听到这个人的问题后，说，
If I hear this person's problem and say,
“你有没有想过要去看心理医生?”。
"Have you thought about seeing a therapist?".
这不是一个诚实而开放的问题，
That's not an honest open question,
因为它实际上是一个劝说和伪装,
because it is in fact a speech and disguise,
一个变相的建议。
a piece of advice in disguise.
澄心委员会是我们围绕着
And the clearness committee is where we
不修正、不拯救、不建议、不纠正
do our deepest practice around no fixing,
而进行最深入的实践的地方。
no saving, no advising, no setting straight.
在两个小时或更长的时间里,
So for two hours or more,
委员会里的五六个人
the five or six folks on that committee
向这个人提出诚实而开放的问题,
ask this person honest open questions,
焦点人物在其他人
he or she answers
面前回答这些问题，
those questions in front of the others
如果焦点人物选择这样做的话，而通常他们会这样做。
if they choose to do so and normally they do.
这里的整个意图是
And the whole intent here is
帮助焦点人物揭开
to help this person peel back whatever the layers are
那些阻止他或她无法
that keep him or her from
听到内在导师声音的那些东西。
hearing the voice of the inner teacher.
贵格会的理解是，
The Quaker understanding is that
每个人都在自己的内心深处
every person has within himself or herself
拥有所需的真理，拥有处理
the truth needed, the resources needed
这个问题或议题所需的资源，
to deal with that problem or issue
无论它们多么令人烦恼。
no matter how vexing it is.
我们最不需要的就是
The last thing we need is advice
从别人的生活中导入的建议;
imported from someone else's life;
我们最不需要的就是有人说,
the last thing we need is someone saying,
“如果我是你，我会这么做”,
well, if I were in your shoes, here's what I do,
因为我们没有站在彼此的角度考虑问题，
because we aren't in each other shoes,
只是管窥一豹而已。
we stand in our own solitude.
这是一个尽力尊重这一点的过程，
And this is a process that tries to honor that,
在尊重独处的同时，
but at the same time while honoring solitude
将社区的资源用于
bringing the resources of community
解决这个人的问题。
to bear on that person's problem.
真正关键之处在于，
What's really critical to understand  is
这种做法不仅使我们摆脱了
that this jerks us out not only of
我们的建议习惯和倾向，
our advising habits and tendencies,
而且也摆脱了我们如下的观念，
but also of our notion that
即我们被投身在地球上
somehow we were put on earth
是为了解决彼此的问题...
to solve each other's problems...
因此，我总是对人们说，
So I always say to people that
在澄心委员会期间,
during a clearness committee,
我们的任务只是把一个人放在我们的
the task is simply to hold a human being
手中和心中，就像一个人手握着一只小鸟一样。
in our hands and hearts as one would hold a small bird.
随着委员会工作的进行,
And that as the committee goes along,
在那两三个小时的时间里，
they're going to be at least three temptations
委员们至少会有三个诱惑。
over that two or three hour period.
一个是，过了一段时间,
One is that after a while,
我们的手开始围着那只小鸟转，
the hands start to close around that bird
我们开始解剖、分析和挑剔。
and we start to dissect and analyze and pick apart.
遇此情况，我会说，让我们与这种倾向作斗争,
And I say that let's fight that tendency,
让我们保持双手张开，并握住那只鸟。
let's just keep the hands open and hold that bird.
第二个诱惑是在一个小时之后，
A second temptation is going to be after an hour
我们感受到自己的手和胳膊有点沉重，
so to kind of feel the weight of one's own hands and arms,
这只鸟其实并不重，
the bird doesn't really weight anything,
灵魂非常轻。
the soul is very light.
但在此期间维护、参与
But the holding, the attending,
并集中注意力是困难的，要求很高。
the paying attention it is difficult and demanding.
因此，我们会开始想
And so that we're going to
把那只鸟放下来。
start wanting to put that bird down.
我要求人们也要与这种倾向作斗争，
And I ask people to fight that tendency as well,
只要两三个小时而已，
it's just two or three hours and
我们可以握着这只鸟的。
we can hold the bird for that long.
然后第三个，也是最后一个倾向是，
And then the third and final tendency is
在我们和焦点人物
that somewhere towards the end of
共度了两三个小时，
the clearness committee process
在问了诚实而开放的问题后，
after we've sat with this person
在澄心委员会过程
for two or three hours and we've asked
接近尾声的某个地方，这是很难做到的。
honest open questions and it's very hard to do this.
我们将开始
We will start moving
这样移动双手，飞吧，小鸟，飞吧，
the hands this way, fly, fly,
你没有领会吗，你还不明白吗，快飞吧，
don't you get it, don't you see it, take off,
向我们展示你学到了什么。
show us that you have learned something.
我们也要抵抗这种诱惑。
And we're to fight that temptation as well.
我们被召唤要做的所有事情
All in the world were called to do
就是恭恭敬敬地捧着那个人。
is to hold that person respectfully attentively.
并且渴望唤起
And with a desire to evoke the voice of
焦点人物内心导师的声音,
that person's inner teacher,
不是为了我们，而是为了焦点人物的利益。
not for our sake but for that person's sake.
等澄心委员会过程结束后,
And when the committee process is over,
我们可以简单地把手收回到心里，
we can simply withdraw those hands into the heart and
只要我们愿意，可以在我们的余生里
hold the person there for as long as we want,
一直捧着这个人。
for the rest of our lives.
我认为这是人类
I think it's what the human self most yearns for
在这个世界上最渴望的，那就是被尊重地捧着,
in this world is to be held respectfully,
不是被入侵，不是被修正,
not to be invaded, not to be fixed,
不是被纠正，而只是被尊重地捧着。
not to be set straight, but just to be held respectfully.
而当这种情况发生时，
And when that happens,
最令人惊奇的成果会随之而来。
the most amazing consequences ensue.